2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5 W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



CURRICULUM VITAE

SRA Locum Template

It is of importance that all our CVs are received in the same format. We appreciate if you could fill this template out and return to <u>info@sralocum.com</u>. Should you have any questions please contact: Shahid Ali, Locum Coordination Consultant, SRA Locum (00353 1 685 4700).

Personal profile:

Name: Residential Address:	Dr. Rabia Batool APT 39 A Stradbrook Stradbally road Portlaoise Co. Laois Ireland
-------------------------------	---

Eircode	R32NA48
Email:	drrabiabatool@gmail.com

Date of birth.	22/09/1985
Marital status:	Married.
Nationality:	Pakistani

Professional Summary

Well-respected work experience in treating patients for a variety of conditions. Board Certified

in Medical Practitioner of Pakistan Medical and Dental Council (PMDC). Areas of interest include Obstetrics and Gynaecology. Skilled in the evaluation and management of patients in various disciplines of Obs/Gynae including labor rooms, HDU, Obs/Gynae wards, OPDs, Infertility Clinics, Contraception, Menopausal and Urogynaecological clinics and emergency. Performed independently vaginal deliveries, Operative vaginal deliveries, Cesarean section(primary and repeat) and simple gynaecological procedures like ERPC Hysteroscopy, diagnostic dilatation & curettage, endometrial ablation, suction and evacuation of molar pregnancy, Bartholin abscess, PPH, cervical & vaginal tears, B Lynch, uterine artery ligation, polypectomies. Trained in performing routine obstetrics and gynaecological ultrasound scans

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



.Assisted and performed under direct supervision and assistance TAH, VH, peripartum hysterectomy, bladder repair ruptured uterus repair, laprotomies for ruptured ectopic pregnancy, major degree placenta previas. Assissted TOT, LAVH, Total Laproscopic hysterectomy

Laproscopic Tubal Ligation, Laproscopic cystectomy, Diagnostic Laproscopy, Myomectomies, Staging Laprotomies. Performed Regularly audits in the department along with thrice weekly morning meetings. Actively involved in doing presentations in department. Involved in the teaching of undergraduate medical students and junior fellows in the department. Excellent reputation for patient service and superior clinical skills.

Work Experience

- House Physician 26-09-2009 to 25-03-2010 (6 months)
- Medical Unit II, Holy Family Hospital, Rawalpindi Pakistan.
- House physician 26-03-2009 to 25-09-2009 (6 months)
- Gynae and Obs Unit II, Holy Family Hospital, Rawalpindi Pakistan.
- **PGT (OBS GYNAE)** 18-07-2011 to 04/07/2015 (4 years)

Gynae Unit-II, Holy Famil Hospital, Rawalpindi Pakistan.

- **SHO** 13/07/2015 to 10/07/2016 (1 year)
- Midland Regional Hospital Mullingar.
- **SHO** 11/07/2016 to 08/01/2017 (6 months)

Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise

• Registrar 09/01/2017 to 09/07/2017 (6 months)

Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise.

- FCPS Exam Preparation 10/07/2017 to 29/09/2018
- MRCOG Preparation 01/10/2018 to 29/04/2019
- Registrar 08/07/2019 TO Date

Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise Ireland

Education

Degree	Board/University	Result Declared On
MRCOG	Royal College Of Obstetricians And Gynaecologist	29-05-2019
FCPS	Fellowship of College of Physicians and	27-09-2018

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



	Surgeons, Pakistan	
MRCPI	Royal College of Physicians Ireland	18-11-16
PRES	Medical Council of Ireland	25-04-18
MBBS	Punjab Medical College, Faisalabad Pakistan.	13-02-09
FSC	FBISE Islamabad Pakistan,	28-07-03
MATRICULATION	FBISE Islamabad Pakistan	25-06-01

Affiliations

- Pakistan Medical and Dental Council (B-55435-P)
- Irish Medical Council.(413688)
- General Medical Council UK

Certifications

- Certificate of primary surgical skills by CPSP.
- Certificate of Basic Life Support by CPSP/HSE.
- Certificate of Introduction to computer and internet by CPSP
- Certificate of Research methodology, biostatistics and Dissertation writing By CPSP
- Certificate of Communication skills by CPSP.
- Certificate of Emergency Obstetric Care (EMOC) by Holy Family Hospital, Rawalpindi Pakistan
- Certificate of Postmiscarriage Care by Holy Family Hospital, Rawalpindi Pakistan
- K2 Perinatal Training

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



Audit/QIP:

- Audit on Administration of postnatal analgesia at MRHP Maternity.
- QIP on Decision to Delivery interval Variation in Cat 1 & Cat 2 LSCS AT MRHP.

Abstracts/E-Posters:

 Abstract /E –Poster JOGS November 2020(Administration of postnatal analgesia at MRHP)

Courses:

- UCD Course Graduate Certificate Obstetric Ultrasound (Jan 2021)
- RCPI Course Leadership in Clinical Practice
- RCPI Practical scenario module on Fetal monitoring
- RCPI Practical scenario module on PPH

Researches:

- National (Pakistan)
- "Comparison of intramuscular progesterone versus placebo in prevention of recurrent preterm labor after arrested preterm labor" (Approved by CPSP)
- International
- Member of world women trial of tranexamic acid for treatment of postpartum hemorrhage (London School Of Hygiene And Tropical Medicine)

Scholarships and Awards:

- Selected for Health Services executive(HSE Ireland) CPSP Scholarship programme 2015-2017
- Selected as the Best trainee of Obstetric unit 2 holy family hospital Rawalpindi April 2015.

Continuing Professional Development(CPD):

- Attended and participated in various educational activities (Internal and external CPD)
- Attended workshop on operative vaginal delivery, fetal blood sampling, Implanon, neonatal resuscitation, MVA.
- Attended 6th Annual conference on Medical problems in Pregnancy at RCPI

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com
E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

P: 01-0854/00 & 01-0994

Fax: 01-6852538

Ireland.

References

Will be furnished on demand

